<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<slideshow>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki" image="1.png">
		<text>The atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki were nuclear attacks during World War II against the Empire of Japan by the United States of America under US President Harry S. Truman.</text>
		<text>On August 6, 1945 the nuclear weapon Little Boy was dropped on Hiroshima by the crew of the Enola Gay, directly killing an estimated 80,000 people and completely destroying approximately 68% of the city's buildings. In the following months, an estimated 60,000 more people died from injuries or radiation poisoning.</text>
		<text>At about 07:50 Japanese time on the morning of August 9, 1945, an air raid alert was sounded in Nagasaki, but the "all clear" signal was given at 08:30. When only two bombers were sighted at 10:53, the Japanese apparently assumed that the planes were only on reconnaissance and no further alarm was given. At 11:01 the "Fat Man" weapon was dropped over the city's industrial valley. According to some estimates, about 70,000 of Nagasaki's 240,000 residents were killed instantly, and up to 60,000 were injured. An unknown number of survivors from the Hiroshima bombing made their way to Nagasaki and were bombed again.</text>
		<text>After the nuclear attacks, Hiroshima was rebuilt and the closest surviving building to the location of the bomb's detonation was designated the Genbaku Dome or "Atomic Dome", a part of the Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park. The suffering of the bombing is the root of Japan's postwar pacifism, and the nation has sought the abolition of nuclear weapons from the world ever since.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Syncretism" image="2.png">
		<text>Most Japanese people incorporate the features of many religions in their daily lives in a process known as syncretism. Many people, especially those in younger generations, claim to feel that the religions in Japan are part of the traditional culture. The same person may have a wedding at a Christian church and have a funeral at a Buddhist temple. Japanese streets are decorated on Tanabata, Obon, Halloween and Christmas.</text>
		<text>While it has been the backbone of the Japanese culture from ancient times, between the 16th to the 19th century Shintoism flourished. Today Shintoism has reverted to a more peripheral role in the life of the Japanese people. The numerous shrines are visited regularly by local believers and, if they are historically famous or known for natural beauty, by many sightseers. Many marriages are held in the shrines, and children are brought after birth and on certain anniversary dates; special shrine days are celebrated for specific occasions, and numerous festivals are held throughout the year, often drawing huge crowds at the larger shrines. Many homes have "god shelves", kamidana, where offerings can be made to Shinto deities.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Death" image="3.png">
		<text>Most Japanese funeral services are held in a Buddhist style. The following is a description of a Japanese funeral. Of course, there exist many variations.</text>
		<text>On the funeral day the body is cremated. The guests take a first meal during that time in the crematorium. Afterwards, the relatives pick the bones out of the ash and pass them from person to person by chopsticks.</text>
		<text>The actual funeral ceremony is then held by Buddhist monks according to Buddhist rituals. Many guests are present at this ceremony. Each of them will pay about 20,000 Yen to the relatives and receive a small gift in return. At last, another meal is held.</text>
		<text>The urn is put on an altar at the family's house and kept there for 35 days. Incense sticks (osenko) are burned there around the clock (special 12 hour sticks for the night exist). Many visitors will come to the house, burn a stick, and talk to the family. After 35 days, the urn is finally buried on a Buddhist cemetery.</text>
		<text>In Buddhist temples, such as Zojoji, hundreds of small Jizo statues line a fence next to a quiet pathway. These small statues are used in the burial ceremonies of infants (mizukokuyo). Jizobosatusu is the protector of the souls of stillborn children, and mothers who have lost an unborn child may dedicate an image of the deity and decorate it with baby clothes and toys. At Zojoji these statues are often dressed and frequently have small windmills making for a colorful display in sharp contrast to the sad circumstances surrounding their origin.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Custom cars" image="4.png">
		<text>In the 1970s and 80s Japanese motor companies produced many popular performance cars and performance versions of existing cars. However, many of these were never exported beyond Asia. In the late 1980s and early 1990s, "grey imports" of Japanese performance cars became abundant in Western Europe and North America, such as the Toyota Supra. Many factors, such as parts being interchangeable, the low cost of obtaining a used imported car, and networking and e-commerce via the Internet all allowed the expansion of the practice of modifying a low-cost compact car.</text>
		<text>Because of their light weight and the increasing availability of low-cost tuning equipment, economy cars and compact cars exhibit high performance, at a relatively low cost in comparison to dedicated sports cars. As professional sporting and racing with such vehicles increased, so did more recreational use of these vehicles. Drivers with little or no automotive, mechanical, or racing experience would modify their vehicles to emulate the more impressive versions of racing vehicles with mixed results.</text>
		<text>"Rice burner" is a pejorative used initially to describe Japanese-made motorcycles and automobiles. Many variations have also been used, such as rice rocket for Japanese sport bikes. Bippu (pronounced vippu, or commonly known as V.I.P. or VIP Style in the west) refers to the modification of Japanese luxury automobiles to make them more fashionable and even more luxurious.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Drifting" image="5.png">
		<text>Modern drifting started out as a racing technique popular in the All Japan Touring Car Championship races over 30 years ago. Motorcycling legend turned driver, Kunimitsu Takahashi, was the foremost creator of drifting techniques in the 1970s. He was famous for hitting the apex (the point where the car is closest to the inside of a turn) at high speed and then drifting through the corner, preserving a high exit speed. This earned him several championships and a legion of fans who enjoyed the spectacle of burning tires.</text>
		<text>A street racer named Keiichi Tsuchiya became particularly interested by Takahashi's drift techniques. Tsuchiya began practicing his drifting skills on the mountain roads of Japan, and quickly gained a reputation amongst the racing crowd. In 1977, several popular car magazines and tuning garages agreed to produce a video of Tsuchiya's drifting skills. The video, known as Pluspy, became a hit and inspired many of the professional drifting drivers on the circuits today.</text>
		<text>The third film in the The Fast and the Furious series, Tokyo Drift, is set in a romanticized version of Japan's drift culture. The film very loosely depicts the Japanese drift-racing environment. However, little to no street racing -- such as that depicted in the feature -- takes place in major Japanese cities, and the majority of racing is undertaken on licensed tracks or on touges (mountain passes).</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="Traditional Clothes" image="6.png">
		<text>Kimono are the traditional garments of Japan. Originally kimono was used for all types of clothing, but it came to refer specifically to the full-length garment that is still worn by women, men, and children. Kimono are T-shaped, straight-lined robes that fall to the ankle, with collars and full-length sleeves.</text>
		<text>Kimono can be expensive. A woman's kimono may easily exceed £5,000; a complete kimono outfit, with kimono, undergarments, obi, ties, socks, sandals and accessories, can exceed £10,000.</text>
		<text>Today, kimono are usually worn only on special occasions, and mostly by women. A few older women and even fewer men still wear kimono on a daily basis. Men wear kimono most often at weddings and for the tea ceremony. Kimono are also worn by both men and women in certain sports, such as kendo. Professional sumo wrestlers frequently wear kimono because they are required to wear traditional Japanese dress whenever appearing in public outside the ring.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="School" image="7.png">
		<text>The Japanese word for uniform is seifuku.</text>
		<text>In many areas, primary school students do not need to wear a uniform to school. Both boys and girls wear brightly coloured caps to prevent traffic accidents. The Japanese junior and senior high school uniform traditionally consists of a military style uniform for boys and a sailor outfit for girls. While this style of uniform is still in use, many schools have moved into more western school uniform styles. These uniforms consist of a white shirt, tie, blazer with school crest and trousers for boys and a white blouse, tie, blazer with school crest and tartan skirt for girls.</text>
		<text>The sailor outfit (sera-fuku) is a common style of uniform worn by female middle school and high school students. It was modelled after the uniform used by the British Royal Navy. Imitation sailor outfits are a popular style of costume for Halloween and other party events and is sold at department stores and costume shops throughout Japan. School uniforms are prominent in the popular Japanese comics Sailor Moon, Cardcaptor Sakura, Zatch Bell! and InuYasha (as worn by Kagome Higurashi). The Tekken video game characters Asuka Kazama, Ling Xiaoyu and Miharu Hirano all wear school uniforms. Go-Go Yubari, an assassin from the movie Kill Bill, is famous for wearing a school uniform.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="Pokemon" image="8.png">
		<text>Pokemon was created in 1995 and has become the second most successful videogame series in the world, falling only behind Nintendo's Mario series. The concept of Pokemon stems from the hobby of insect collecting, a popular pastime which Pokemon creator Satoshi Tajiri had enjoyed as a child. Players of the games are designated as "Pokemon trainers", and the two general goals for such trainers are to collect all of the available Pokemon species found in the game, and train a team of powerful Pokemon from those caught to compete against the teams of Pokemon owned by other trainers.</text>
		<text>Each year from 1999 to 2006 has seen the release of a feature length movie. There is another Pokemon movie scheduled for release in 2007. The Pokemon anime series and films are a set of adventures featuring Ash Ketchum as the main character, following his quest to become a Pokemon Master. He and his companions travel around the Pokemon world battling other Pokemon trainers. Accompanying Ash on his journeys were Brock, the Pewter City Gym Leader; Misty, the youngest of the Gym Leaders sisters from Cerulean City; and later on, Tracey Sketchit, an artist and 'Pokemon watcher' who accompanied them in the Orange Islands in the second saga.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="Cosplay" image="9.png">
		<text>Cosplay comes from the English words "costume" and "play", and is centered around dressing as characters from comic books and video games, and, less commonly, Japanese television shows, fantasy movies, or Japanese pop music bands. As a hobby, people gather to see each others' costumes, show off their own handmade creations, take lots of pictures, and possibly participate in best costume contests. The costume contest is often a test of skill, design, and audience reaction. The contestants are judged either before hand or on stage and then walk across said stage while the audience cheers.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Life of a Sumo wrestler (Rikishi)" image="10.png">
		<text>The type and quality of a Sumo wrestler's dress depends on the wrestler's rank. Rikishi in Jonidan rank and below are allowed to wear only a thin cotton robe called a yukata, even in winter. Furthermore they must wear a form of wooden sandals called geta when outside. Similar distinctions are made in general life. The junior rikishi must get up earliest, around 5 a.m., for training whereas the sekitori may start around 7 a.m. When the sekitori are training the junior rikishi may have chores to do, such as assisting in cooking the lunch, cleaning and preparing the bath, or holding a sekitori's towel for him for when he needs it. In the afternoon the junior rikishi will again usually have cleaning or other chores to do, while their sekitori counterparts may relax, or deal with work issues related to their fan clubs. Thus the world of the Sumo wrestler is split broadly between the junior rikishi, who serve, and the sekitori, who are served. Life is especially harsh for new recruits, to whom the worst jobs tend to be allocated, and there is a high dropout rate at this stage.</text>
		<text>The negative effects of the sumo lifestyle become dangerously apparent later in life. Sumo wrestlers have a life expectancy of between 60 and 65, more than 10 years shorter than the average Japanese male. They often develop diabetes and high blood pressure, and are prone to heart attacks.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Modern sumo" image="11.png">
		<text>Sumo is a non-competitive contact sport where two wrestlers called rikishi face off in a circular area. The sport is popular in Japan and is surrounded by ceremony and ritual. The Japanese consider Sumo a gendai budo: a modern Japanese martial art, even though the sport has a history spanning many centuries. The Sumo tradition is very ancient, and even today the sport includes many ritual elements, such as the use of salt for purification, from the days Sumo was used in the Shinto religion.</text>
		<text>Professional Sumo is practiced exclusively in Japan, where it originated, but wrestlers of other nationalities participate. Former Yokozuna Musashimaru, a Samoan born Hawaiian, became the second foreigner to reach sumo's top rank in the late 1990s. The current Yokozuna Asashoryu is Mongolian and is presently (in 2004 and 2005) the dominant force in the sport. Asashoryu heads a small group of Mongolian wrestlers who have achieved Sekitori status. Wrestlers further afield from Eastern Europe countries such as Georgia and Russia have also found success in the upper levels of Sumo. In 2005 Kotooshu from Bulgaria became the first wrestler of European origin to attain Ozeki ranking. There are currently 59 rikishi officially listed as foreigners.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Sushi" image="12.png">
		<text>In Japanese cuisine, sushi is a food made of vinegared rice combined with various toppings or fillings, especially seafood, but also vegetables, mushrooms, eggs, or meat. Most, but not all, fish used in sushi is raw; other ingredients may be cooked, blanched, sauteed, or marinated. There are various types of sushi. Sushi served rolled in nori (dried sheets of laver, a kind of pressed and dried alga) is called maki (rolls). Sushi made with toppings laid onto hand-formed clumps of rice is called nigiri; sushi made with toppings stuffed into a small pouch of fried tofu is called inari; and sushi made with toppings served scattered over a bowl of sushi rice is called chirashi-zushi, or scattered sushi.</text>
		<text>In Japan, and increasingly abroad, conveyor belt sushi/sushi train (kaiten zushi) restaurants are a popular, cost effective way of eating sushi. At these restaurants, the sushi is served on color-coded plates, with each color denoting the cost of that sushi it contains. The plates are placed on a conveyor belt or boats floating in a moat. As the belt or boat passes, the customers choose their desired plate. After finishing, the bill is tallied by counting how many plates of each color have been taken.</text>
		<text>Unusually for Japanese food, sushi can be eaten either by hand or by chopsticks. Traditionally, one should start with white-fleshed or milder-tasting items and proceed into darker, stronger-flavored varieties later. Only the fish (not the rice) should be dipped into soy sauce, which should be used sparingly. In top-end sushi restaurants, it is considered bad form to request or add extra wasabi, as the chef has (or should have) already placed a suitable amount in each morsel.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Eating etiquette" image="13.png">
		<text>It is customary to say itadakimasu ("I shall receive") before starting to eat a meal, and gochiso-sama deshita ("That was a feast") to the host after the meal and the restaurant staff when leaving.</text>
		<text>The rice or the soup is eaten by picking the relevant bowl up with the left hand and using chopsticks with the right. Bowls of soup, noodle soup or ochazuke may be lifted to the mouth but not white rice. Soy sauce is not usually poured over food at the table; a dipping dish is usually provided. In particular, soy sauce should never be poured onto rice or soup. Blowing one's nose at the table is considered extremely offensive. Noodles are slurped.</text>
		<text>Chopsticks are never left sticking vertically into rice, as this is how they are ritually offered to the dead. Using chopsticks to spear food, to point, or to pass food into someone else's chopsticks is also frowned upon.</text>
		<text>When taking food from a communal dish, unless they are family or very close friends, turn the chopsticks around to grab the food; it is considered cleaner. If sharing with someone else, move it directly from one plate to another; passing food from one pair to another is a funeral rite.</text>
		<text>It is customary to eat rice to the last grain. Being a fussy eater is frowned upon, and it is not customary to ask for special requests or substitutions at restaurants. It is considered ungrateful to make these requests especially in circumstances where you are being hosted, as in a business dinner environment. Good manners dictate that you respect the selections of the host.</text>
		<text>Even in informal situations, drinking alcohol starts with a toast (kanpai) when everyone is ready. It is not customary to pour oneself a drink; but rather, people are expected to keep each other's drinks topped up.</text>
	</section>
</slideshow>