<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<slideshow>
	<section subject="Traditional religion" image="1.png">
		<text>In general, traditional Kenyan religions involve belief in an eternal, unique and omnipotent creator God who is distant from mankind, but not out of reach. God created and maintained the universe, including man, who in many cosmologies was lowered from some other world. Essentially, the Kenyan concept of God is similar to both the Muslim and Christian ideas. The name given to God changes from people to people, though those most frequently encountered are Ngai, Enkai, Akuj, Mulungu and Mungu, and variations thereof.</text>
		<text>God cannot be seen, and usually resides in the sky or on high mountains. God is associated with rain (and by extension grass, certain plants, animals, mountains, rainbows and prosperity), as well as with the consequences of not providing rain (drought, famine, disease and death). God is also manifest in the sun, moon, thunder and lighting, stars and in trees, especially the wild fig tree, which is sacred to many different Kenyan peoples.</text>
		<text>The majority of the Africans in Kenya are now members of the Roman Catholic, Anglican, and other Protestant churches. Although the modern religions are dominant, many Kenyans still follow traditional religions. Kenya has managed to integrate colonial and traditional beliefs together.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Modern religion" image="2.png">
		<text>The population in Kenya follows three major, modern religions. Thirty-eight percent of the Kenyon population is Protestant, twenty-eight percent are Roman Catholic, and six percent are Muslim. The remaining people are followers of various traditional religions.</text>
		<text>Christian missionary activity began the 1840s, notably with the combined evangelical and exploratory activities of Johann Ludwig Krapf and Johannes Rebmann, who were incidentally also the first Europeans to set eyes on Mount Kenya. The following decades though saw few converts and little concerted effort to diffuse the Christian faith into Kenya. The building of the Uganda Railway from Mombasa to Kampala at the turn of the century, however, changed all that. From the end of the nineteenth century, the interior was opened up to both colonists and missionaries, the two often working hand-in-hand. After scattered successes, the 1920s and 1930s saw a rash of church building, not all of them controlled by the government's approved denominations.</text>
		<text> Apart from the African population, Kenya is home to various ethnic groups that immigrated during colonial rule from India and Pakistan. Referred to in Kenya as Asians, they are divided on the basis of religious affiliation into Hindus, Muslims, and Sikhs. Although many left after independence, a substantial number remain in urban areas such as Mombasa, Nairobi, and Kisumu.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Masai Mara" image="3.png">
		<text>The Maasai Mara (also spelled Masai Mara) is a large park reserve in south-western Kenya. Named for the Maasai tribespeople (the traditional inhabitants of the area) and the Mara River which divides it, it is famous for its exceptional population of game and the annual migration of the wildebeest. From July to October, the promise of rain and fresh life giving grass in the north brings more than 1.3 million Wildebeest together into a single massive herd. They pour across the border into the Mara, making a spectacular entrance in a surging column of life that stretches from horizon to horizon. At the Mara River they mass together on the banks before finally plunging forward through the raging waters, creating a frenzy as they fight against swift currents and waiting crocodiles.</text>
		<text>The Mara has been called the Kingdom of Lions and these regal and powerful hunters dominate these grasslands. Cheetah are also a common sight in the Mara, as are Hyena and smaller predators such as Jackals.</text>
		<text>Traditionally, the Maasai rarely hunt and living alongside wildlife in harmony is an important part of their beliefs. Lions and Wildebeest play as important a role in their cultural beliefs as their own herds of cattle.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Mountains" image="4.png">
		<text>Kenya is a land of contrasts, and nowhere is this more apparent than in its range of altitudes. The hills and mountains of Kenya are a world apart from the lowland valleys and plains.</text>
		<text>Mt Kenya, Africa's second highest peak is regarded as the realm of Ngai, god of the local Kikuyu people. Traditionally, all Kikuyu home were built to face this sacred peak. They call it Kirinyaga, or place of light. The mountain is an awe-inspiring sight. Its ragged series of peaks are crowned with snow, and its slopes are thick with forest. The mountain is best seen at dawn, when the days early light silhouettes its impressive summit high over the surrounding plains.</text>
		<text>Rising from the jungles that border Uganda, Mt Elgon is an impressively craggy extinct Volcano. The mountain has many caves for the visitor explore. In these caves, known collectively as Elkony, ancient cave paintings decorate the walls, and bats and rock hyrax are found among the winding passageways. The most famous cave of all is Kitum, where each night Elephant herds gather and begin a slow procession deep into the mountain. The elephants make their way through the caves, following well worn paths made by generations before them. Deep in the cave, they use their tusks to excavate the walls, seeking the natural salt which they lick from the scarred rock.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Athletics" image="5.png">
		<text>Kenya is active in several sports, among them football, rallying, rugby, cricket and boxing. But the country is known chiefly for its dominance in long-distance athletics. Kenya has regularly produced Olympic and Commonwealth Games champions in various distance events, especially in 800m, 1,500m, 3,000m steeplechase, 5,000m, 10,000m and the marathons. Kenyan athletes (particularly Kalenjin) continue to dominate the world of distance running, although competition from Morocco and Ethiopia has somewhat reduced this supremacy.</text>
		<text>The Marathon world record holder, Paul Tergat, and the four-time women's Boston Marathon winner and former world champion, Catherine Ndereba, are among the best-known athletes in Kenya. After a dramatic, gutsy finish - Kenya’s Martin Lel became the 2007 London Marathon Champion in a time of 2:07.42.</text>
		<text>Retired Olympic and Commonwealth Games champion Kipchoge Keino, who helped usher in Kenya's ongoing distance dynasty in the 1970s even before fellow Commonwealth Champion Henry Rono's spectacular string of world record performances, is currently Kenya's most famous sportsman.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Safari Rally" image="6.png">
		<text>In the motor rallying arena, Kenya is home to the world famous Safari Rally, commonly acknowledged as one of the toughest rallies in the world, and a part of the World Rally Championship for many years until its exclusion after the 2002 event due to financial difficulties. Some of the best rally drivers in the world have taken part in and won the rally, such as Bjorn Waldegaard, Hannu Mikkola, Tommi Makinen, Shekhar Mehta and Colin McRae. Though the rally still runs annually as part of the Africa rally championship, the organisers are hoping to be allowed to rejoin the World Rally championship in the next couple of years.</text>
		<text>In 2006 history was made when George Mwangi navigated Azar Anwar to victory becoming the first Kenyan-African to ever win the Safari in its 54 year history.</text>
		<text>After the loss of the Safari Rally from the World Rally Championship in 2002, rally enthusiasts led by Mike Kirkland and Surinder Thatthi decided to recreate the nostalgia of "The Safari" by creating an alternative rally, reverting to the unique characteristics of the East African Safari Rally. The idea was to allow only classic cars built before 1974 and to avoid the powerful turbo charged and 4WD drive cars. The stages, or sections would be longer and the service crews and back up would be limited just like in the early days.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Drought and famine" image="7.png">
		<text>According to the United Nations world food programme, Northern Kenya is on the verge of catastrophe. In many areas the herdsmen have lost 80% of their animals. As 3m people - including 1.6m children - face starvation, the wooded hills and vast plains of the region have become killing fields. Rival clans are fighting over scarce grazing and dried-up water holes. With little material support from the government in the prosperous south - best known to Britons for its exclusive safari park lodges and luxury beach resorts - the northern herdsmen have resorted to theft and atrocity. In April heavy rainstorms broke the drought, but the deluge failed to restore the vegetation that once sustained livestock, whose rich milk and siphoned blood were a staple diet. Flash floods have washed away topsoil and devastated unpaved roads, making relief and policing hazardous.</text>
		<text>As Oxfam and the Catholic charity Cafod highlighted appeals to assist northern Kenya last week, lack of security was affecting the ability of the aid agencies to travel in the region. Armed 'home guards', the only local security, are taking sides across the tribal divides.</text>
		<text>"When people are starving they will stop at nothing to ensure their survival," said Joseph Semal, a development officer in Isiolo.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Corruption" image="8.png">
		<text>It is estimated the average urban Kenyan pays 16 bribes per month. There is also corruption on a larger scale with each of the last two government regimes being criticised for their involvement.</text>
		<text>On March 2nd 2006, the offices of Kenya's second largest TV and newspaper companies were raided simultaneously by groups of masked police officers.  Hooded men carrying AK-47 assault rifles raided the headquarters of the Standard media group just after midnight. Staff were kicked and beaten and forced to lie on the floors as offices were searched and equipment taken away, the Standard newspaper said on its website. The TV station was taken off the air for 13 hours, and the newspaper's press was damaged and its uncirculated copies burned. The government Security Minister John Michuki later admitted that the Government organised the simultaneous raids. The press had recently published a number of articles examining continued allegations that corruption has cost Kenya $1bn - nearly a fifth of its state budget - under the current administration led by President Mwai Kibaki.</text>
		<text>Ironically, in June 2006, the head of the Kenyan office of a global anti-corruption watchdog was sacked over allegations of financial and other irregularities. The board of directors of Transparency International Kenya said it had sacked Mr Mati because of "major anomalies and irregularities in contracts awarded to a company run by persons with links to the executive director" and the misuse of Transparency International's name for financial gain.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="Art and Crafts" image="9.png">
		<text>The art of carving was practiced throughout Kenya to produce both functional and decorative items. The Kamba people are considered the best Kenyan carvers, and have long been known as skilled woodworkers. Anyone who has been to Kenya will undoubtedly have come across the miniature carvings of elephants and antelopes, lions, reptiles and birds, as well as the necklace pendants embellished by coiled wire, which are sold in hotel gift shops and tourist stalls throughout the country. No matter where you see or buy them, chances are that they will have been made by the Kamba.</text>
		<text>Begun by a Kenyan who learned the art of woodcarving while serving in the British Army during the First World War, the woodcarving industry now has an export value of $20 million, with the majority of carvings sent to Europe, the United States, Canada and Japan. However, researchers have found that nearly all tree species used for carvings have now been severely depleted in the wild, threatening the future of one of Kenya's most successful small industries. Conservation organisations such as the WWF have urged tourists and importers to buy 'good wood' carvings from from well managed forests in Kenya in order to reduce pressure on over-exploited tree species.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="child" subject="Body decoration" image="10.png">
		<text>Many Kenyan traditional societies placed great significance on decoration of the body. In tribes such as the Kuria and the Samburu, this was raised to the form of high art. The Samburu place great significance on physical beauty and adornment, especially among warriors, who take great care with their physical appearance, using hair styling and ochre body painting to create an impression of great delicacy. It was this trait that earned them their name Samburu (Butterflies), given to them by other tribes. For the Maasai, the use of decorative beading is extremely significant, and jewelrey is used to emphasize social status and to signify stages of initiation and passage.</text>
		<text>Ancestry is very important to the African people to show honour to their ancestors. Masks are designed and decorated with elaborate hair and jewelry to show great wealth, and honor to their ancestors. Masks are greatly revered in African culture and many masks are used in ceremonies, generally depicting deities, spirits of ancestors, mythological beings, good and or evil spirits, the dead, animal spirits, and other beings believed to have power over humanity.</text>
	</section>
</slideshow>