<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<slideshow>
	<section subject="Baseball" image="1.png">
		<text>Baseball was introduced to Cuba in the 1860s by Cubans who studied in the United States and American sailors who ported in the country. The sport quickly spread across the island nation. Soon after this, the first Cuban War of Independence against its Spanish rulers spurred Spanish authorities in 1869 to ban playing the sport in Cuba. The reasons were because Cubans began to prefer baseball to viewing bullfights and as such, baseball became symbolic of freedom to the Cuban people.</text>
		<text>In late 1878 the Cuban League was organized, consisting of three teams: Almendares, Habana, and Mantanzas. The teams were amateurs and all whites. The Spanish-American War brought increased opportunities to play against top teams from the United States. Also, the Cuban League admitted black players beginning in 1900. Soon many of the best players from the Northern American Negro Leagues were playing on integrated teams in Cuba. Beginning in 1908, Cuban teams scored a number of successes in competition against major league baseball teams, behind outstanding players such as pitcher Jose Mendez and outfielder Cristobal Torriente. By the 1920s, the level of play in the Cuban League was superb, as Negro League stars like Oscar Charleston and John Henry Lloyd spent their winters playing in Cuba.</text>
		<text>The Cuba national baseball team is made up of amateur players from the Cuban National League and has participated in every Summer Olympic Games since 1992. It has been the most successful team at the Olympics. In the four tournaments contested, they have won the gold medal three times and the silver once.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Boxing" image="2.png">
		<text>From 1972 through 2004, Cuba and the United States have won the most Olympic Gold Medals in boxing, 29 for Cuba and 21 for the U.S. "Boxing is well suited to the Cuban character," said legendary boxing coach Alcides Sagarra. "We are brave, resolute and selfless. We have strong convictions and clear definition. We are pugnacious and we like to fight." "Cuban fighters smell fear in their opponents," said WBO former heavyweight champ Michael Bentt. "If they can intimidate you, they've got you. They psychologically steamroll guys."</text>
		<text>One reason for the unusual success in men's boxing, and sports in general, may be that Cubans identify sports talent at a young age. Potential athletes are "nurtured" at special schools where athletics are more rigorously explored. A law passed in 1962 made professional sports illegal in Cuba hence Cubans stay amateurs for their complete careers. As such there are two options faced by a high-profile athlete in Cuba; remain in Cuba and become a hero of the revolution, or a leave and become a wealthy professional athlete in the USA-slash-traitor. Lovers of the sport and boxing insiders point out that since Cuba's impressive dominance in amateur competition began in 1972, no Cuban has dominated their weight class upon becoming professional. A critical factor for this lackluster performance may be the number of perks and distractions available to successful athletes in capitalist cultures. Coming from a relatively impoverished society, and suddenly having access to everything that money can buy, will hamper even the strictest level of concentration. This can suddenly become the biggest challenge faced by young boxers, and by the time they figure out how to handle their new wealth, the clock and the forces of nature are no longer on their side.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Cigars" image="3.png">
		<text>Cigars manufactured in Cuba are widely considered to be without peer, although many experts believe that the best offerings from Honduras and Nicaragua rival those from Cuba. Cuban cigars are rolled from tobacco leaves found throughout the country of Cuba. The filler, binder, and wrapper may come from different portions of the island. All cigar production in Cuba is controlled by the Cuban government, and each brand may be rolled in several different factories in Cuba. Cuban cigar rollers are claimed to be the most skilled rollers in the world.</text>
		<text>Cigars are often presented as stereotypical rich man's accessory. Cigars are often smoked to celebrate good fortune, like the birth of a child, a graduation, a big business accomplishment, etc. Some buy and keep a cigar 'for luck' with regard to a bet, with the intention of smoking it after winning the bet. The expression "close, but no cigar", said after a near miss, derives from that tradition.</text>
		<text>The Cuban cigar became inextricably intertwined with U.S. political history on February 7, 1962, when United States President John F. Kennedy imposed a trade embargo on Cuba. Americans were thus prohibited from purchasing what were at the time considered the finest cigars on the market, and Cuba was deprived of a large portion of its customers. According to Pierre Salinger, Kennedy's press secretary, the president ordered him on the evening of February 6 to obtain a thousand Cuban cigars; upon Salinger's arrival with the cigars the following morning, Kennedy signed the order which put the embargo into effect. As of 2007, it remains illegal for Americans to purchase or import Cuban cigars.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Music" image="4.png">
		<text>The roots of most Cuban musical forms lie in the cabildos, a form of social club among African slaves brought to the island. The cabildos were formed from the Igbos, Araras, Bantu, Carabalies, Yorubas, and other civilizations/tribes. While Cuban music has its principal roots in Spain and West Africa, over time it has been influenced by diverse genres from different countries. Most important among these are France, the United States, and Jamaica. Reciprocally, Cuban music has been immensely influential in other countries, contributing not only to the development of jazz and salsa, but also to Argentinian tango, Ghanaian high-life, West African Afrobeat, and Spanish "nuevo flamenco".</text>
		<text>In the 1930s, the Lecuona Cuban Boys and Desi Arnaz popularized the conga in the US and Don Aspiazu did the same with son montuno, while Arsenio Rodriguez developed the conjunto band and rumba's popularity grew. Conjunto son, mambo, chachacha, rumba and conga became the most important influences on the invention of salsa. In the 1940s, Chano Pozo formed part of the bebop revolution in jazz, playing conga and other Afro-Cuban drums. Conga was integral part of what became known as Latin jazz, which began in the 1940s among Cubans in New York City. Modern Cuban music is known for its relentless mixing of genres. In the 1970s and onwards, son montuno was combined with other Latin musical forms, such as the mambo and the rumba, to form contemporary salsa music, currently immensely popular throughout Latin America and the Hispanic world.</text>
	</section>
	<section subject="Dance" image="5.png">
		<text>Cuba is famous both for its ballet performers and for developing famous dances such as conga, rumba, salsa and the cha-cha-cha.</text>
		<text>The National Ballet of Cuba is one of the top ballet companies in the world. Through the Ballet Nacional and its network of schools, Alicia and Fernando Alonso have created a uniquely Cuban style of dance. Earning worldwide acclaim, the Ballet has performed in 58 countries and received hundreds of international awards.</text>
		<text>The conga dance originated in the Latin-American carnivals tradition, where its simple rhythm and steps encouraged mass participation. The name refers to the Cuban conga drum which was used to beat out the rhythm. In Cuba, the conga is known today under the name Comparsa. The dancers form a long, processing line. It has three shuffle steps on the beat, followed by a kick that is slightly ahead of the fourth beat.</text>
		<text>The rumba influence came in to Cuba in the 16th century with the slaves from Africa. The cha-cha-cha is a Cuban dance that became popular in the 1950s, invented by a violinist and composer named Enrique Jorrin. The well-known name came into being with the help of dancers; it was discovered that their feet were making a peculiar sound as they grazed the floor on three successive beats: cha-cha-cha.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Spanish colonialism" image="6.png">
		<text>Cuba was a Spanish possession for 388 years, ruled by a governor in Havana, with an economy based on plantation agriculture and the export of sugar, coffee and tobacco to Europe and later to North America. It was seized by the British in 1762, but restored to Spain the following year. The Spanish population was boosted by settlers leaving Haiti when that territory was ceded to France. As in other parts of the Spanish Empire, a small land-owning elite of Spanish-descended settlers held social and economic power, supported by a population of plebian creoles, mixed-race small farmers, laborers and African-descended slaves.</text>
		<text>In the 1820s, when the other parts of Spain's empire in Latin America rebelled and formed independent states, Cuba remained loyal, although there was some agitation for independence. Cuba's proximity to the U.S. has been a powerful influence on its history. Throughout the 19th century, Southern politicians in the U.S. plotted the island's annexation as a means of strengthening the pro-slavery forces in the U.S., and there was usually a party in Cuba which supported such a policy. In 1848, a pro-annexationist rebellion was defeated and there were several attempts by annexationist forces to invade the island from Florida. There were also regular proposals in the U.S. to buy Cuba from Spain. During the summer of 1848, President James Knox Polk quietly authorized his ambassador to Spain, Romulus Mitchell Saunders, to negotiate the purchase of Cuba and offer Spain up to $100 million, an astonishing sum of money at the time for one territory. Spain, however, refused to consider ceding one of its last possessions in the Americas.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Independence" image="7.png">
		<text>In April 1895, a war was declared, led by the writer and poet Jose Marti who proclaimed Cuba an independent republic - Marti was killed at Dos Rios shortly after landing in Cuba with the eastern expeditionary force. His death immortalized him and he has become Cuba's undisputed national hero. The Spaniards retaliated with a campaign of suppression. General Valeriano Weyler was appointed military governor of Cuba, and as a repressive measure he herded the rural population into what he called reconcentrados. These reconcentrados were the prototype for 20th century concentration camps. Estimates that between 200,000 and 400,000 Cuban civilians died from starvation and disease during this period in the camps.</text>
		<text>In 1897, fearing U.S. intervention, Spain promised home rule with an elected legislature. The rebels rejected this offer and the war for independence continued. Shortly afterwards, on 15 February 1898, the U.S. battleship Maine was mysteriously blown up in Havana harbor, killing 266 men. Forces in the U.S. favoring intervention in Cuba seized on this incident to accuse Spain of blowing up the ship. The result was the Spanish-American War, in which U.S. forces landed in Cuba in June 1898 and quickly overcame the exhausted Spanish resistance. Theodore Roosevelt succeeded McKinley as President of the United States and granted the Republic of Cuba formal independence on 20 May 1902. Cuba today does not celebrate May 20 as their date of independence, but instead October 10, as the first declaration of independence and the day Castro and his army entered Havana, January 1, 1959, as "the triumph of the revolution".</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="Revolution" image="8.png">
		<text>In 1956 a party of rebels, including Fidel Castro, landed in a boat from Mexico and tried to start an armed resistance movement in the Sierra Maestra. In Mexico, his army got strengthened by Ernesto Che Guevara. By late 1958, the rebels had succeeded in breaking out of the Sierra Maestra and launched a general insurrection, joined by hundreds of students and others fleeing Sergeant Fulgencio Batista's crackdown on dissent in the cities. When the rebels captured Santa Clara, east of Havana, Batista decided the struggle was futile and fled the country to exile in Portugal and later Spain. Castro's rebel forces entered the capital on January 1, 1959.</text>
		<text>Fidel Castro became Prime Minister of Cuba in February 1959, and has held effective power in the country until temporarily handing it over to his brother, Raul Castro, for medical reasons in July 2006. During 1959, Castro's government carried out measures such as the confiscation of private real estate, the nationalization of public utilities, and the suppression of the widespread corruption that had developed under Batista, including closing down the gambling industry. Castro also evicted many Americans, including mobsters from the island. Summary executions of suspected Batista collaborators, coupled with the seizure of Cuban-owned businesses and the rapid demise of the independent press, nominally attributed to the powerful pro-revolution printing unions, raised questions about the nature of the new government.</text>
	</section>
	<section ageGroup="adult" subject="The Cold War" image="9.png">
		<text>In October 1959, Castro openly declared himself to be friendly towards Communism, though he did not yet claim to be a Communist himself, while the liberal and other anti-Communist elements of the government were purged. Many who had initially supported the revolution fled the country to join the growing exile community in Miami. In the context of the Cold War, the U.S. saw the establishment of a Soviet base of influence in the Americas as a threat and plans were approved to remove Castro from power. The result was the disastrous Bay of Pigs Invasion of April 1961. President John Kennedy withdrew promised US air support for the invading force at the last minute and they were routed. This prompted Castro to declare Cuba a socialist republic, and himself a Marxist-Leninist in May of 1961.</text>
		<text>One immediate strategic result of the Cuban-Soviet alliance was the decision to place Soviet intermediate range ballistic missiles in Cuba, which precipitated the Cuban missile crisis of 1962, during which U.S. President John F. Kennedy threatened the Soviet Union with nuclear war unless the missiles were withdrawn. The idea to place missiles in Cuba was brought up either by Castro or Khrushchev, but agreed by USSR from the reason that the U.S. had their nuclear missiles placed in Turkey and elsewhere in Middle East, thus directly threatening USSR safety. In 1965, Castro merged his revolutionary organizations with the Communist Party, of which he became First Secretary and in 1976 introduced a new constitution under which he became President himself.</text>
	</section>
</slideshow>